Well, this is it.
It's time to finish this thing off.
So to finish off this game, we're going to add in a few more sound effects and then add some background
music.
So let's start with the easiest because I mean who doesn't like doing the easiest stuff first.
But we want to add some nice background sound to our project.
So clicking on our backdrop sprite, we can add in a when flag clicked and a forever loop.
Then moving to the sounds tab and hovering over this button, we can then select Upload Sound.
And here we can select a background sound from our Music and Sound Effects folder.
For this game we can use Funk Casino.
Then moving back to our code, we can drag in the play sound until done, block and select func casino
or whatever sound you uploaded.
And hitting play.
Notice how much better that is.
And also notice how our sound effect for our car works a lot better and actually sounds quite good.
So with that done, let's move to our next sound effect, which is our car skidding sound effect.
And here, basically what we want to happen is have our car make a skidding sound when we hit into an
obstacle.
So moving over to our player sprite, we can add in this sound.
So clicking on the sounds tab and choosing a sound, we can then search for skid.
Which is this one here.
So selecting it and moving back to our code.
Now what we want is for our car to play this skidding sound when it touches an obstacle.
So if you look at the script here, this is basically the script that senses if our car is touching
an obstacle.
So all we need to do is add in this play skid sound to the start of each of these if checks.
So adding one to each, we can then hit play when hitting an obstacle.
And yeah, that's not quite right.
But basically what is happening is our play Skid sound is interfering with our other code.
Because if you look at the script, it plays the skid sound until it is done before it moves to the
next blocks of code.
So to fix this, all we need to do is remove all these play skid sounds until done blocks and replace
them with this start sound skid.
And with that, we can hit play again.
It is an obstacle.
And there you have it.
That's much better.
Now, before we wrap up this lesson, there is just one more thing, and that is changing the pitch
of our obstacle course so that as these cars pass by at a faster speed, it sounds faster to.
So moving over to our obstacle course sprite, all we need to do is grab a when flag clicked, then
this set pitch block and set the pitch to zero, which is basically setting it to default when the game
starts.
Then grab a forever loop, and then we can put this change pitch effect by block inside our loop.
And finally, to make sure the pitch doesn't instantly go extremely high, we can add a weight block
and change it to, let's say, 10s.
And I'll let you test that out for yourself, because we've reached the end of our lesson and the end
of our section, and we've completed this game.
Really, really great work on getting this far.
You have certainly accomplished a lot.
So give yourself a good pat on the back because you really do deserve it.